JONATHAN EYLER-WERVE

Email: jonathan@eylerwerve.com Web: eylerwerve.com/jonathan Mobile: +1 312.725.4045

Product owner, designer & front-end programmer for social benefit Web applications. Experience in for-profit, non-profit and hybrid startups, including ecommerce, online activism and collaboration tools.

"Jonathan is **great at managing the big picture** of business directions. He has **excellent sense in**product usability. He is brilliant technically and has all the skills in designing and implementing product
UI and data architecture."

- Yan Cheng, Chief Architect, AOL (1995-2009); Indaba engineering lead (2009-2013)

EXPERIENCE

Moxie Jean / moxiejean.com

VP, TECHNOLOGY (2012-2013)

Product owner for venture-funded e-commerce startup. Designed and implemented transition from subscription to e-commerce model in two weeks; currently offering 8,000 items updated weekly. Designed user experience, system architecture and brand identity to exceed industry conversion benchmarks every month since August 2012 launch. Designed and implemented A/B testing, email marketing, SEO, SEM, display advertising, knowledge management, content marketing, ad creative, merchandising design, product photography, video editing, support ticketing, warehouse IT.

Raised \$400,000 in angel funding on 25% month-over-month revenue growth over 6 months.

Community Media Workshop / communitymediaworkshop.org DIRECTOR, CHICAGO SUMMIT PROJECT (2012)

Published ChicagoStories.org, a NATO Summit reporting help desk for the City of Chicago, in two weeks. Coordinated editorial and marketing teams, managed funders and partner organizations, while writing all frontend code, identity and graphic design.

Finalist for Golden Trumpet Award from the Publicity Club of Chicago (winners to be announced).

Global Integrity / globalintegrity.org

DIRECTOR, TECHNOLOGY & INNOVATION (2009-2012)

Global Integrity provides original reporting, data, technology and process innovation to the global anticorruption movement. First employee; contributed directly to all aspects of Global Integrity, particularly operations, community building and technology. Helped raise \$3 million in foundation funding.

Product Owner and Director, Indaba Fieldwork Platform / getindaba.org

Conceived, funded, designed and implemented a \$500,000 publishing platform for public interest media organizations currently in use in 100+ countries and all 50 US states. Empowered small teams

to manage large distributed networks and publish data using best-practice sharing standards. Adopted by Public Radio International, the World Wide Web Foundation and others. Catalyzed a community of practice on distributed reporting and data publishing across 14 organizations.

Product Owner, Foglamp / foglamp.org

Directed identity and website for a revenue-generating global reporting network, which provides overseas investors with deal-specific insights on governance, corruption and related risk. Clients include Bloomberg L.P. and McKinsey & Company.

Workshop facilitator, Global Integrity Dialogues

Directed anti-corruption workshops with governments, civil society, academics, faith leaders and media in Cambodia, East Timor, Indonesia, Papua New Guinea, Philippines and Vanuatu. Also trained activists in Cairo and Amman on anti-corruption prior to the Arab Spring.

DIRECTOR, OPERATIONS (2006-2009)

Product Owner, Global Integrity Report / www.globaintegrity.org/report

Created a 1,200+ person, 100+ country network of reporters and researchers which has published 4 million words of original reporting on government efforts to fight corruption. Created online tools and technology platforms to facilitate care and feeding of this network by only 4 project managers. Managed internal and remote community of 250+ contributors, editors, designers and engineers.

The Global Lives Project / globallives.org BOARD OF DIRECTORS (2008-2009)

Implemented content management, workflow management, and relationship management tools for start-up volunteer documentary film network, which has since exhibited 200+ hours of original film.

Sparks Custom Publishing

FOUNDER (2005-2007)

Created and managed a distributed network of journalists and editors working online as on-demand editorial and design capacity to non-profit organizations. Profitably employing 10 people in year one.

The Center for Public Integrity / publicintegrity.org

PROJECT MANAGER & GRAPHIC DESIGNER (2002-2004)

Designed Web technology for project that spun off to become Global Integrity.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Arts, Colorado College. Major: Political Science. Minor: Journalism

PORTFOLIO SITES

MoxieJean.com – Product owner, identity and UI designer, system architect, all code.

GlobalIntegrity.org/Report – Product owner, identity and UI designer, system architect.

ChicagoStories.org – Team lead, product owner, identity and UI designer, system architect.

SocialTechCensus.org – Early stage team lead, information architect, identity design.

Foglamp.org – Product owner, identity and UI design, system architect.

OpenGovPartnership.org – Product owner, general contractor to White House.

IndabaPlatform.com – Team lead, product owner, identity and UI designer.

Sites built on Indaba:

thewebindex.org, government.defenceindex.org, stateintegrity.org

COMPETENCIES

Have taught:

- Product design for the Web (presentations to World Wide Web Foundation, Nonprofit Software Development Summit; Chicago COUNTS)
- Metrics and interpretation (presentations at Presidio School of Management, United Nations Development Program, others; published in 4 languages)
- Online collaboration systems (presentations to Web Foundation, Chicago COUNTS)
- Social media strategy and community building (workshops by Community Media Workshop)
- Social venture strategy (presentations at Georgetown, SAIC).

Proficient:

- HTML5 / CSS for desktop and mobile
- Graphic design including print, digital, identity design, and interaction.
- Ecommerce, advanced knowledge of Shopify's Liquid templating language.
- WordPress administration and theming; Drupal administration and theming.
- Data models, relational database administration, basic SQL, Advanced Excel, basic SPSS.
- SEO, website performance tuning, basic server administration, CDNs, system architecture.
- SEM, ad networks, retargeting and related strategy.
- Studio, stock and editorial photography; photo post-production; basic video shooting and editing.

Familiar:

• Javascript, PHP, Ruby on Rails, Flash, Actionscript.

WEB DESIGN AWARDS

ChicagoStories.org. Finalist, Publicity Club of Chicago's "Golden Trumpet" *globalintegrity.org.* Winner, Ashoka "Changemakers" Contest.

The Global Integrity Report. Winner, APEX Award (Awards of Excellence 2008).

The Politics of Oil. for publicintegrity.org. Winner, Society of Environmental Journalists Award for Outstanding Online Reporting; Winner, Sigma Delta Chi Award for Investigative Reporting Online (Independent); Finalist, Investigative Reporters and Editors (Online).

ONLINE JOURNALISM AWARDS

"Internet Censorship: A Comparative Study," Author. Winner, *Every Human Has Rights* Media Award. *Windfalls of War*, Contributing author. Winner, George Polk Award for Internet Reporting.

Making a Killing: The Business of War, Researcher. Winner, Sigma Delta Chi Award for Investigative Reporting Online (Independent); Finalist, ONA Online Journalism Awards, Enterprise Reporting (Independent).

The Water Barons, Researcher. Winner, Investigative Reporters and Editors award (Online Journalism); Finalist, ONA Online Journalism Awards (Enterprise Reporting).

REVIEWS

- "Can I just say THANK YOU MOXIE JEAN for building a website that is clean and easy to navigate...
 This one is so clean and lovely and just, yes." whoorl.com
- "Had a look at Indaba -- and I'm blown away. This is exactly what a number of investigative journalism teams that I collaborate with have been looking for." -- Justin Arenstein, Knight Fellow
- "The Chicago Stories site is brilliant... really useful." -- Christina Lamb, Sunday Times bureau chief
- "By far the best primer on corruption I've read." -- Samuel Rubenfeld, Wall Street Journal
- The Global Integrity Report "has been a very important global trend-setter"... Global Integrity's work is unique... a must read." -- P. Radhakrishnan, Asian Tribune

REFERENCES

Contact information available on request.
All quoted text published on LinkedIn or organization blogs.

Alix Dunn

Founder, the engine room

Allen "Gunner" Gunn

Founder, Aspiration

Aron Pilhofer

Director of Interactive News, The New York Times

Chuck Lewis

Founder, The Center for Public Integrity

David Evan Harris

Founder, the Global Lives Project

Demetrio Magidad

Director of Strategic Design, LimeRed Studio

"I have had the pleasure to work with Jonathan on a number of occasions. His work at Community Media Workshop overseeing our ChicagoStories website and NATO Summit work helped position the organization as a reliable source for information on the Summit. He is a forward thinking person who was fun to work with. His **vast knowledge of current trends in technology** will provide any company the advancement they need to stay ahead. I highly recommend Jonathan on any position or project that requires strategic thinking and practical solutions."

Jen Shelby

Head of Marketing and Acquisition, Moxie Jean

"Heading up marketing at Moxie Jean, I have had the opportunity to work with Jonathan on a variety of projects. His **leadership in establishing strong processes** and technical capacity, allow us to execute quickly and stay nimble. He is strategic in his approach to projects and as someone who has worked in many early stage companies, a huge plus. He also has a wonderful sense of humor-- equally valuable during deadlines.

Juan Gonzolez

Strategy Leader, EchoDitto

"Jonathan is a strong information architect with a powerful command of the needs of constituencies to create truly compelling user experiences. I had the pleasure of working with Jonathan on a multinational initiative, and Jonathan's guidance on functional needs of users enabled me to create effective pathways of engagement for those users. I would welcome the opportunity to work on web or digital media projects with Jonathan again and highly recommend him!"

Justin Massa

Founder & CEO, Food Genius

Monika Shepard

Technology and Community Manager, Global Integrity

"I worked with Jonathan at Global Integrity where he was one of the visionaries of the Indaba platform, which is a set of tools that help groups of people gather and publish information. He was the **lead designer ensuring the usability of the platform**. Jonathan is a very creative and passionate person who is great with technology."

Nathaniel Heller

Co-founder, Global Integrity

"Jonathan was employee #1 at Global Integrity and has played an instrumental role in the organization's growth during the past several years, particularly our embrace of technology and, eventually, the creation of the Indaba fieldwork platform... when Global Integrity spun off from the Center in 2005 Jonathan was the first person we called when assembling our small start-up staff.

Over time, Jonathan helped to move Global Integrity towards cloud-based technology years before the term was popular; we have never owned and operated a single server and don't plan to thanks to his foresight. The creation of the MAGIC fieldwork platform in 2006 marked Jonathan's second attempt to improve upon the tools used for distributed data gathering. By 2009 he was already looking years into the future with a short thought paper that envisioned what would eventually be called Indaba. Three years later, we and a growing number of partner organizations use Indaba daily to manage thousands of contributors in 100-plus countries to gather best-of-breed data and reporting.

Jonathan has made huge contributions to Global Integrity, and his **humor**, **good nature**, **and collaborative approach** to solving problems will be missed."

Thom Clark

Executive Director, Community Media Workshop

"Jonathan joined our team to manage an editorial outreach project providing story frames and news source lists to help international journalists in Chicago for the May 2012 NATO Summit discover the real city beyond staged diplomatic photo opps and protestors in the streets. On a very quick turnaround over four months, he managed over 20 editorial "briefing papers," designed and posted same on a very attractive website ChicagoStories.org and worked with our team to contact European media outlets to alert them to our story development work. Over long hours Jonathan proved creative and technically proficient to deliver content to over 8,000 unique visitors with some 43,000 page views."

Ory Okollah

Director of Policy (Africa), Google Co-founder, Ushahidi

Updated 2013/05/06